(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-29T04:27:08.817854",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
目指せよ快眠
Aim for deep sleep,
勝ち取れ安眠
Claim peaceful slumber,
いざ夢の世界へ
Now, off to the world of dreams!
理想の眠りを求めて
Seeking the ideal sleep,
さあ始めよう
Now, let's begin—
おやすみ
Good night.
(ノンレム睡眠レム睡眠)
(Non-REM sleep, REM sleep)
私は囚われの姫
I am a captive princess,
魔王の城の中で
Inside the Demon King's castle,
独り閉じ込められては
Shut away all by myself,
毎日ひたすらに眠ってます
Sleeping earnestly day after day.
今宵も布団に入り
Tonight, too, I crawl into bed—
すやすやリスト生活
The peaceful slumberist life!
枕もシーツも硬くて眠れない
Pillow and sheets are too stiff to sleep...
(君も寝具にしてやろうか!)
(Shall I turn you into bedding too?!)
目指せよ快眠
Aim for deep sleep,
勝ち取れ安眠
Claim peaceful slumber,
いざ夢の世界へ
Now, off to the world of dreams!
ふかふかの枕を手に入れて
Getting a fluffy pillow,
この疲れ癒したい
I want to heal this fatigue!
恐れず前進
Marching forward without fear,
ほぐせよ全身
Relaxing my entire body,
瞼を閉じたなら
The moment I close my eyes—
すべすべのシーツの上で
Upon the smooth, soft sheets,
さあ始めよう
Now, let's begin—
おやすみ
Good night.
(ノンレム睡眠レム睡眠)
(Non-REM sleep, REM sleep)
私は囚われの姫
I am a captive princess,
悲鳴が響く夜に
In a night echoing with screams,
一人で牢を抜け出し
Breaking out of the cell alone,
今日もお散歩へと行ってきます
I'm off on today's stroll as well!
幾多の試練を越えて
Overcoming numerous trials,
新たな寝具の元へ
Towards a brand new bedding!
マグマで
In magma,
もどくで
in toxic waste,
死んでも眠りたい
I want to sleep even if I die.
城ごと寝具にしてやろうか！
Shall I turn the whole castle into bedding?!
目指せよ快眠
Aim for sound sleep,
勝ち取れ安眠
claim peaceful slumber!
いざ夢の向こうへ
Now, heading beyond the dream,
ハイテク目覚まし
get a high-tech alarm clock
手に入れて気持ちよく目覚めたい
and wake up feeling refreshed!
まだまだ前進
Still advancing further,
華麗に変身
transforming brilliantly!
ごはんを食べたなら
Once you've eaten your meal,
魔法のベッドにダイブして
dive into a magical bed!
さあ始めよう
Now, let's begin,
おやすみ
good night.
明日はもっと 今日よりずっと
Tomorrow will be even more, far more than today,
いい夢見れるかな
I wonder if I can see a good dream.
フワフワの羽根に包まれて
Wrapped in fluffy feathers,
ココロ行くまで眠りたい
I want to sleep to my heart's content.
目指せよ快眠
Aim for sound sleep,
勝ち取れ安眠
claim peaceful slumber!
いざ夢の世界へ
Now, into the world of dreams,
理想の眠りを求めて
seeking the ideal slumber!
さあ始めよう
Now, let's begin,
おやすみ
good night.
もうあと5分 おやすみ
Just 5 more minutes, good night...
ノンレム睡眠レム睡眠ノンレム睡眠レム睡眠
Non-REM sleep, REM sleep, non-REM sleep, REM sleep...
スヤァ
Syaa...
あー... はい、こんばんすー！
Ah... Yes, good evening-su!
ほらライブ3期生の白銀ノエルでーす！
It's Hololive 3rd Gen Shirogane Noel!
本日はライブに来てくれてありがとうございます！
Thank you very much for coming to the live today!
そしてハッシュタグはこちら！白銀ノエル生誕祭2025たくさんスクショしてSNSに投稿してください！
And the hashtag is right here! Please take lots of screenshots of Shirogane Noel's Birthday Festival 2025 and post them on SNS!
今日の、えーライブのテーマなんですが、ま、見てのとおりね、睡眠・安眠・癒やしライブとなっております。
Today's, um, live theme is, well, as you can see, sleep, peaceful slumber, and healing live.
ライブ後半にかけて盛り上がっていくのでね、ぜひ皆さまも盛り上がってください！
It's going to get more exciting towards the second half of the live, so everyone please get hyped too!
てな感じで、え、1曲目は、え、快眠・安眠・スヤリスト生活を歌わせていただきました！
So, um, for the first song, um, I sang "Sound Sleep! Peaceful Slumber! Sylist Life"!
あの曲中のね、あの、団長踊りながら、ま、変身したシーンがありましたけど、分かった？
In that song, um, Dancho was dancing while, well, transforming, did you notice?
分かったってか、みんな気づいてる？ていうか、おめめが、ちょっと変わりました。お気づきでしょうか？
Did you notice? I mean, did everyone notice? My eyes changed a bit. Have you noticed?
ま、具体的にね、どういうところが変わったかといいますと、あの、髪の毛がですね、あの、サラサラになりました！
Well, specifically, if you ask what changed, um, my hair became, um, silky smooth!
ええ、サラサラになって、特に後ろとかね、分かるかな？ほら、サラサラ！もう本当に、いつでも、あの、シャンプーのCM待ってます！
Yeah, it became silky smooth, especially the back, can you tell? See, silky smooth! I'm really waiting for a shampoo commercial anytime!
ってな感じでサラサラになったのと、あとおめめもね、あの、ちょっと、変わっております。
So it became silky smooth, and my eyes also changed a bit.
えーとなんか、だいさん、のえちゃんが怒るようなこと言ってて、お、お、え、何？おい
Um, like, Daisan said something that made Noe-chan angry, oh, oh, eh, what? Hey!
ちょっと太った！ん、何？太ってないよ！最近ダイエット頑張ってるもん！
A little fat! Huh, what? I'm not fat! I've been working hard on my diet recently!
てな感じで、前はちょっと結構ガチ怒りって感じだったんですけど、マイルド怒りになりました。はい。
So before, it was pretty seriously angry, but now it's mild anger. Yes.
っていう感じで、あの、ちょっとね、いろんな表情ができるようになったので、それも踏まえて、あの、ライブ見てくれると嬉しいです。
So, um, since I can make various expressions now, I'd be happy if you watched the live taking that into account too.
そして、まのえちゃんも変わったんですけど、この変わったね、あの、お姿で、さらに本日のステージは、こちらです！
And, Noe-chan also changed, but in this changed appearance, furthermore, today's stage is right here!
えー、すごいね、全景、わー！
Um, amazing, panoramic view, wow!
なんか本当に癒やしって感じだよね、もう本当にきれいに、はい、作っていただきました。
It really feels like healing, right? They really made it so cleanly, yes.
ま、ここのね、周り、そう、周りね、これ雲？雲の海みたいな、感じで、プーカ、プーカってなっていまーす。えー！
And the surroundings here, right, the surroundings, is this clouds? Like a sea of clouds, it goes puka, puka. Yay!
そしてね、ま、こうやってね、雲の海から、上もね、すごい！きれい！なんか、飾りが、ぐるぐるぐるぐると、回っておりますので、
And, um, like this, from the sea of clouds, above too, amazing! Beautiful! Like decorations spinning round and round,
いやなんかね、あの、ま、これから、ちょっと、ゲストパートとかもあるんですけど、なんかそれに合わせて、いろいろと変わっていくみたいなので、ぜひ楽しみにしてみてください。
so um, well, from now on, there's also a guest part and stuff, and it seems various things will change to match that, so please look forward to it.
それでは、次の楽曲、レッツ・ゴー！
Well then, the next song, let's go!
僕は今夢旅の中
I am now in the middle of a dream journey...
Now, I'm on a journey toward my dream
あの星の島まででも飛んでゆける
I can fly until I reach that star's island...
手のりウタうたう
Playing and singing
僕のユメクイ
my dream-eater
君のそばにも辿り着ける
And reach your side...
最初に描いた夢を
If you can't remember the first
思い出せなくなったのは
Dream you had sketched out,
大人になったから？
Could it be because you've grown up?
右か左かでいつまでも迷って
To go right or left? Forever lost
太陽が反転するまでしゃべりこんだ
Talking until the sun rolls over
一つだけポケットに入れてきたもの
The only thing I brought in my pocket
おっきなこの愛を持って
Is this large love
僕は今夢旅の中
Now, I'm on a journey toward my dream
あの星の島まででも飛んでゆける
I can fly until I reach that star's island...
手のりウタうたう
Playing and singing
僕のユメクイ
my dream-eater
君のそばにも辿り着ける
And reach your side...
カラフルな靄に心を奪われ
In the colorful mist my heart was stolen
ちょっとしたことにきまずいた
So I stumbled from the smallest thing
すりむいたところに君がくれたのは
What you gave me for the place I scraped
はずかしいくらいの可愛らしいばんそうこう
Was an embarrassingly cute band-aid
叶えるたびに食いつくすユメクイ
As I make them come true, my dream-eater devours them
叶えるたびにまた夢を見る
As I make them come true, I dream again
いくつになっても
No matter how old I get
僕は今夢旅の中
Now, I'm on a journey toward my dream
あの星の島まででも飛んでゆける
I can fly until I reach that star's island...
寄り道してプレゼントを見つける
Wandering around, I find a present
手のりウタうたう
Playing and singing
僕のユメクイ
my dream-eater
描いた未来に君がいつもいる
In the future I've sketched out, you're always there
僕は今夢旅の中
Now, I'm on a journey toward my dream
あの星の島まででも飛んでゆける
I can fly until I reach that star's island...
手のりウタうたう
Playing and singing
僕のユメクイ
my dream-eater
君のそばにも辿り着ける
And reach your side...
君のそばでずっと夢を見る
I will keep dreaming by your side
半端ないパッパラッパ パッパラッパ
Half-hearted papparappa papparappa
限界突破パッパラッパ パッパラッパ
Limit-breaking papparappa papparappa
毎日半端ないパッパラッパ パッパラッパ
Everyday half-hearted papparappa papparappa
限界突破パッパラッパ パッパラッパ
Limit-breaking papparappa papparappa
明日の私に幸あれ
May tomorrow bring me happiness.
最適温度 煩わしすぎるゴースト
Ideal temperature, an annoying ghost
要所要所の 嫌な外敵要素
Unpleasant external enemies at every turn
何の気ないとお 超あっけらかんと
Carefree and completely nonchalant
悪気もなく邪魔するとか 誰がさにばいばい
Getting in the way without bad intentions, bye-bye to whoever that is.
自分に厳しくタイム確保 五時六時を死守しますと
Being strict with time, defending 5 or 6 o'clock
さらに愛や恋や前も忘れずに ととのうつまり
Without forgetting love, romance, and moving forward, in short, getting balanced
オーバーワークは立ち入り禁止ですよ 手洗い換気もしてますよ
Overwork is strictly prohibited, handwashing and ventilation too
寝長く生きてく まく生きてく 生きてくってもしかしてな
Living long and well... or is that how it goes?
だって安定裏ワザ一網打尽 甘い水には泡がある
Because stability and shortcuts wipe everything out, sweet water has bubbles.
眠くなったら寝る
When I get sleepy, I sleep.
お昼過ぎに起きる
I wake up past noon.
遊びたきゃ遊ぶ
If I want to play, I play.
お腹減ったらご飯を食べる
When I'm hungry, I eat.
嬉しかったら笑う
When I'm happy, I smile.
悲しかったら泣いてもいいんじゃない
When I'm sad, it's okay to cry.
明日の私のために今日も何とか頑張るのさ
For tomorrow's self, I'll somehow do my best today too.
明日も頑張らなくていいように頑張るのさ
I'll do my best today so I don't have to tomorrow.
最大限じゃなくてこれ特捜じゃない やりたいことやっています
Not my maximum, not some special mission, just doing what I want.
誰に知られなくたって別にいいから 私には私のマイルール
It doesn't matter if no one knows, I have my own rules.
明日楽するためにはハイチーズ 意外とこんな感じでラブアンドピースの或る 毎日を生きたいのです
To take it easy tomorrow, say cheese! Surprisingly, I want to live a daily life filled with peace and love.
ドッピードッピードッピしたいと ドッキードッキしたい
Wanting to do doppī-doppī and make my heart go dokki-dokki
レミーレミーレミーしたい明日天気になれ
Wanting remī-remī, hoping tomorrow's weather is good.
ドッピードッピードッピしたい 心もっと撮りたい
Wanting to do doppī-doppī, wanting to capture my heart more.
マンダマンダ自然ブレスデー 毎金トレーニング
Manda-manda natural breath day, every Friday training.
辛くなったら歌う
When it gets tough, I sing.
ぶっかづいたら愚痴る
When things pile up, I vent.
やりたいようにやる
I do as I please.
それができたら苦労しないわ
If it were that easy, I wouldn't struggle.
常に一一自由 してちゃなんてやろうと思ったから
Because I wanted to be free all the time
適当にセーブセディスクは回収してま頑張るのさ
Casually saving and collecting data disks, I'll do my best.
適当にここまでなら言うまいが まあ頑張るのさ
Casually speaking, I won't say much past here, but I'll do my best.
夢の中では ずっとぐうたらしてやるんだ
In my dreams, I'm going to loaf around forever.
誰かのためとかそんなんじゃなくて明日の私のため
Not for someone else, but for tomorrow's me.
ファイト 楽するためには苦しいことも乗り越えちゃうんだからね
Fight! To take it easy, I'll overcome even the painful things.
ファイト やりたくないことやらないためにやりたくないことやれ
Fight! To avoid doing what you don't want to do, do what you don't want to do.
あれこれって結構頑張れてる私ってとっても偉いじゃないか
Isn't a self that works hard at this and that just wonderful?
自分に厳しくタイム確保 五時六時を死守しますと
Being strict with time, defending 5 or 6 o'clock
さらに愛や恋や前も忘れずに ととのうつまり
Without forgetting love, romance, and moving forward, in short, getting balanced
オーバーワークは立ち入り禁止ですよ 手洗い換気もしてますよ
Overwork is strictly prohibited, handwashing and ventilation too
寝長く生きてく まく生きてく 生きてくってもしかしてな
Living long and well... or is that how it goes?
だって安定裏ワザ一網打尽 甘い水には泡がある
Because stability and shortcuts wipe everything out, sweet water has bubbles.
眠くなったら寝る
When I get sleepy, I sleep.
お昼過ぎに起きる
I wake up past noon.
遊びたきゃ遊ぶ
If I want to play, I play.
お腹減ったらご飯を食べる
When I'm hungry, I eat.
嬉しかったら笑う
When I'm happy, I smile.
悲しかったら泣いてもいいんじゃない
When I'm sad, it's okay to cry.
明日の私のために今日も何とか頑張るのさ
For tomorrow's self, I'll somehow do my best today too.
明日も頑張らなくていいように頑張るのさ
I'll do my best today so I don't have to tomorrow.
半端ないパッパラッパ パッパラッパ
Half-hearted papparappa papparappa
限界突破パッパラッパ パッパラッパ
Limit-breaking papparappa papparappa
毎日半端ないパッパラッパ パッパラッパ
Everyday half-hearted papparappa papparappa
限界突破パッパラッパ パッパラッパ
Limit-breaking papparappa papparappa
踊る暇があったら発明して 歌う暇があったら発明して
If you have time to dance, invent something! If you have time to sing, invent something!
ライブのブッキング蹴って発明して そんな発明王にオレはなる
Kick away live bookings and invent! I'm going to be the king of inventors!
踊る暇があったら発明して 歌う暇があったら発明して
If you have time to dance, invent something! If you have time to sing, invent something!
ライブのブッキング蹴って発明して そんな発明王にオレはなる
Kick away live bookings and invent! I'm going to be the king of inventors!
幼少の頃から家で聴いてた音楽はハウスミュージック
The music I listened to at home since childhood was house music.
サブスクのプレイリスト開いて曲ディグったらクラブでDJ
Open my subscription playlist, dig for tracks, and DJ at the club.
パソコン開いたならDTM ソフトはAbleton Live
Open my computer for DTM, the software is Ableton Live.
だけど今作りたいのは蓄音機
But what I want to make now is a phonograph
サークルでの宴会芸 ノリで始めたバンドで
Banquet acts at the circle, in a band started on a whim
なぜかな今はしがないミュージシャン
For some reason, I'm a low-key musician now
まぐれで跨ってメジャーデビュー
Stumbling into a major debut
なぜか今わしがないミュージシャン
For some reason, I'm a low-key musician now
踊るエジソン 自尊心
Dancing Edison, pride
歌うエジソン ジソン心
Singing Edison, self-esteem
踊るエジソン 自尊心
Dancing Edison, pride
歌うエジソン ジソン心
Singing Edison, self-esteem
踊るエジソン 自尊心
Dancing Edison, pride
YouTube を見て得る 1% のひらめき
1% of insight gained from watching YouTube
SNS 通して繋がる発明家のコミュニケーション
Inventor communication connected through SNS
インスタ映え狙った投稿
Posts aimed at being Instagrammable
Webニュースで情報収集
Gathering information from Web news
間違いなくこれからの時代来るのは活動写真
Without a doubt, motion pictures are the future
いや 絶対来ると思うんだけどな
No, I'm sure it's definitely coming
踊る暇があったら発明して
If I had time to dance, I'd invent something
歌う暇があったら発明して
If I had time to sing, I'd invent something
ライブのブッキング蹴って発明して
I'd skip the live booking and invent something
そんな発明王にオレはなる
I will become the king of inventions like that
踊るエジソン 自尊心
Dancing Edison, pride
歌うエジソン ジソン心
Singing Edison, self-esteem
踊るエジソン 自尊心
Dancing Edison, pride
歌うエジソン ジソン心
Singing Edison, self-esteem
踊るエジソン 自尊心
Dancing Edison, pride
今日はこのままさよならじゃないよ
Today, I'll stay like this, it's not goodbye yet
手をとってくれたなら
If you take my hand,
秘密も眠りにつくような夜に
In a night where even secrets fall asleep
君を連れていくよ
I will take you along
それは例えば遠く離れてたって
Even if we were far apart, for instance,
手を繋いでいられるような奇跡のような
Like a miracle where we can hold hands
話をしようよ 窓は開けといて
Let's talk, keep the window open
今日までを思い出して 一つ一つ並べたら
Thinking back until today, if I line them up one by one
明日の雨が気になりだして
Tomorrow's rain starts to weigh on my mind
どうも眠れないみたいだ
It seems I can't sleep at all
変わりたくないことや 変わらなきゃいけないことも
Things I don't want to change, and things I must change
少し忘れたまま 窓の外を眺めていたんだ
Forgetting them a little, I was looking out the window
雨が降り出すその前に
Before the rain starts to fall
君のところまで行けるような気がして 目を閉じてみたんだ
Feeling like I could go to where you are, I tried closing my eyes
そしてこのまま遠くへと行こう
And let's go far away just like this
手をとってくれるかなあ
Will you take my hand?
秘密も眠りにつくような夜を
A night where even secrets fall asleep
君と泳いでいくよ
I will swim with you
街の明かりが消えるたびに笑って 路地裏で抱き合おう
Every time the city lights go out, let's laugh and hug in the back alley
馬鹿みたいな話をしようよ 窓は開けといて
Let's talk about foolish things, keep the window open
聞こえる？
Can you hear?
愛しいことや無くせないものを 教えてくれたのは今日みたいな
What taught me dear things and things I cannot lose is nights like today
夜を重ねて織り上げてきた 私たちに響く音
Layers of nights woven together, the sound that resonates within us
夜が来るたびに 心が踊ってしまうのは
Every time night comes, the reason my heart dances
また一つ 重なっていくから
Is because one more layer is added
目を閉じてみたんだ。
I tried closing my eyes.
今夜、私たちだけで眠ろう。
Tonight, let's sleep just the two of us.
誰にも言わないで。
Don't tell anyone.
君が眠りにつくその少し前に
Just before you fall asleep,
名前を呼んで、
call my name.
叶わない願いに胸は痛んで
My heart aches with unfulfilled wishes,
うつむいてしまうけど
and though I hang my head,
誰もいない街へ誘いに行くから
I'll come invite you to a town where no one is.
今日はこのままさよならじゃないよ
Today is not goodbye, just like this.
手を取ってくれたなら
If you were to take my hand,
秘密も眠りにつくような夜に
to a night where even secrets fall asleep,
君を連れていくよ
I'll take you along.
それは例えば遠く離れていたって
For example, even if we were far apart,
手をつないでいられるような
it feels like we could hold hands.
奇跡のような話をしよう
Let's tell a story like a miracle!
窓は開けておいて、聞こえる？
Leave the window open. Can you hear it?
愛おしいことや無くせないものを教えてくれたのは
What taught me precious things and things that cannot be lost
今日みたいな夜を重ねて織り上げてきた
is what we've woven together, layering nights like today,
私たちに響く音
the sound that echoes for us.
響く言葉
The echoing words...
はーい！ってことで、
Hi there! So,
みなさん今回のライブなんと！
everyone, for this live stream, unbelievably,
新衣装がぽ、ぽ、ぽ、ぽ、ぽ、ぽ、ぽ、ぽ！
we have a new outfit, po-po-po-po!
ありましたー！
it's here!
あのび、びっくりしたかな？びっくりしたんじゃないかなと
Were you surprised? I bet you were surprised,
思います！あのこちらね、すごいあのきらびやかな衣装となっているんですけど、
I think! So this outfit, you know, is super dazzling and gorgeous,
ちょっと今スクショ撮る？えい！
Shall we take a screenshot right now? Yay!
かわいいですかー？
Is it cute?
ぜひあのハッシュタグでね、あのぜひつぶやいてください。
Please be sure to tweet about it using the hashtag.
かわいいでしょ？
Isn't it cute?
なんやらね、このあとちょっと衣装のね色々、あの細部までちょっと見る機会が ariそうな予感がするので
Somehow, it feels like we'll have a chance to look at all the little details of the outfit later,
一旦ねスクショだけお願いしまーす。
so for now, please just take a screenshot!
そして、あとこちらね、見て！
And also, look here!
手首にぷらぷらって紐があるんだけど、これね取れます。
There are dangling ribbons on the wrists, but these can actually be removed.
じゃ、と、と、取ってもらおうかな。えい！えい！
Let's have you take them off. There!
ってことで、はーい！取れます。そう、こちらバージョンもスクショ撮ってもらおう。
And there, see? They come off. Yep, let's get a screenshot of this version too.
かわいいですか？ぴゃあー！
Is it cute? Yay!
ね、すごい愛らしい衣装、ちょっとね、あのドキドキするんですが
Right? It's such an adorable outfit, it makes my heart flutter a bit,
うん！いやあ、なんか、でもちょっと一人寂しいな、なんか、ダインさん...
Yeah! But you know, being all alone feels a little lonely... like, Dain-san...
うっ、あ！ダインかわいい！お、なんかぬずぬずしてる。お、どうしたどうしたどうした！くわあっ！
Oh! Ah, Dain is so cute! He's fidgeting. Hey, what's wrong, what's wrong! Woah!
ダインさんトンデきたー！
Dain-san flew over!
そんなにね、ノエルちゃんに会いたかったんかな？
Did you want to see Noel-chan that much?
かわいいね！いっぱいスクショ撮れた？うーん、ダインさんとのツーショット！
So cute! Did you take lots of screenshots? Yep, a two-shot with Dain-san!
かわいい！え、ないない何？あ、今日は安眠テーマで、あ、ここが違い。あ、なるほどね？
Cute! Wait, what? Ah, today's theme is peaceful sleep, oh, that's the difference. Ah, I see!
曲のリクエスト？あ、子守唄みたいな曲が聴きたい。あ、そうなのダインさん？
Song request? Ah, you want to hear something like a lullaby. Is that right, Dain-san?
じゃあ、せっかくねダインさん来てくれたし、一緒にじゃあ子守唄、うん、じゃあ歌うよ、歌う、なんかちょっと付いてきて、一緒にいくよ！
Well then, since Dain-san came all this way, let's sing a lullaby together! Yep, let's sing, come along with me, let's go together!
おら、おらい！
Here we go!
ぼうやの夢よ
Oh, boy's dreams,
小さな人の子よ
little child of man,
森へ迷い込んだ
wandered into the forest,
大きなこの羽が
these giant wings
ぼうやは見えないのね
you cannot see, can you?
なにも知らない
knowing nothing at all,
まあるいほっぺよ
with your round little cheeks.
ちいさな 人のこよ
Oh, little human child,
森に まよいこんだ
who has wandered into the forest.
大きな この羽が
You cannot see these big wings,
ぼうやは 見えないのね
can you?
なにも 知らない まるい ほっぺよ
Oh, little round cheek, knowing nothing.
ねむれよ ねむれ
Sleep now, sleep.
静かな 水辺においで
Come to the quiet waterside.
ぼうやの 夢は
Your dream will be
竜の 背に 運ばれて
carried on the back of a dragon,
山の 向こうへ 消える
and disappear beyond the mountain.
よろづの 子も
Every child of the world
ならんで ねむる
sleeps side by side.
七つ 数えたら 仲良く 眠ってく
Count to seven, and drift off to sleep peacefully.
なにも 見えない
You can see nothing,
小さな おめめよ
little eyes of yours.
ねむれよ ねむれ
Sleep now, sleep.
草むらへ おいで
Come to the grassy field.
ぼうやの 夢は
Your dream
母さんを 探しては
searching for mother,
空の 向こうへ 帰る
returns beyond the sky.
竜の 背に 運ばれて
Carried on the back of a dragon,
山の 向こうへ 消える
disappearing beyond the mountain.
夕月夜 顔だす 消えてく 子供の声と
The moonlit night shows its face as children's voices fade.
遠く遠く この空の どこかに 君は いるんだろう
You're somewhere in this sky, somewhere far, far away.
夏の終わりに2人で抜け出した この公園で見つけた あの星座 何だか 覚えてる?
Do you remember the constellation we found in the park we sneaked to at summer's end?
会えなくても 記憶をたどって 同じ幸せを見たいんだ
Even without meeting, I trace memories to share the same happiness.
あの香りとともに 花火がぱっと開く
Fireworks burst open alongside that familiar scent.
行きたいよ 君のところへ 今すぐ かけだして 行きたいよ
I want to go to you, rushing there right now.
まっ暗で 何も見えない 怖くても 大丈夫
Pitch black, I see nothing. Even if I'm scared, I'll be fine.
数えきれない 星空が 今も ずっと ここにあるんだよ
Countless starry skies remain right here, just as before.
泣かないよ 昔君と見た きれいな空だったから
I won't cry; this is the beautiful sky I looked at with you
あの道まで 響く靴の音が耳に残る
The sound of your shoes that echoed as far as that street, still remains in my ears
大きな自分の影を見つめて想うのでしょう
You're thinking of it too, aren't you, as you look at your huge shadow
ちっとも変わらないはずなのに
You'd think I wouldn't care at all,
せつない気持ちふくらんでく
but a huge pain swells up
どんなに想ったって君はもういない
No matter how much I think of you, you're gone
行きたいよ 君のそばに 小さくても小さくても
I want to go and be by your side, I may be small, I may be small
1番に君が好きだよ 強くいられる
But I love you more than anything, and it makes me strong
願いを 流れ星に そっと 唱えてみたけれど
I tried to make a quiet wish on a shooting star
叶わないよ 届かないよ きれいな空に
It won't come true, it won't reach you, in the beautiful sky
会えなくても記憶をたどって
Even if I can't see you, I want to trace back over our memories
同じ幸せを見たいんだ
and feel that same happiness
あの香りとともに 花火がぱっと開く
The fireworks burst open, with that scent
行きたいよ 君のところへ 小さな手をにぎりしめて
I want to go to where you are, and take your little hand
泣きたいよ それはそれはきれいな空だった
I want to cry, this is, this is, that beautiful sky
願いを 流れ星に そっと 唱えてみたけれど
I tried to make a quiet wish on a shooting star
泣かないよ 届かない想いをこの空に
I won't cry, I'll send the love that won't reach you into this sky...
もう何十回も 何百回も 霞むソラ見上げて
For the tens, for the hundreds of times, I look up at the dimming sky
辿り着いた場所が 運命のダイヤモンド
The place I've reached is a diamond of destiny
何千回も 何万回も 涙流したきみへ
To you, who has shed tears for the thousands, for the tens of thousands of times
ねぇ 諦められたことはあったっけ？
Hey, has there ever been a time when you were forced to give up?
「憧れ＝限界」だから もういらないよ
Because "longing = limit" is something I don't need anymore
そこに留まるなんて もったいないでしょ？
It would be such a waste to stop here, wouldn't it?
それぞれの物語 交差する瞬間を 見つめる意味は
The meaning of staring at the moment our individual stories intersect
放った夢だけ 大きな弧を描いて
Only the dreams I've let fly will draw a large arc
はちきれそうな煌めきを 消えることなく どこまででも
That brilliance, which is about to burst, will not fade, anywhere
世界の向こうに 届けよう
Let's deliver it to the other side of the world!
終わることのない この胸の衝動は
This unending impulse in my chest...
どうしたって どうしても ぼくを呼んでいたから
No matter what, because it was calling me,
その先へと 走り続ける
I will keep running beyond that.
次へ 次へ 次へ
To the next, to the next, to the next!
妄想だって 中途半端な 浅いなさかかえて
Holding onto half-baked, shallow delusions...
立ち尽くしていた通り雨
A passing rain where I stood still.
雨はプレリュード 何千回も 何万回も
The rain is a prelude, thousands, tens of thousands of times...
挑み続けたきみへ
To you who kept on challenging.
ねえ 聴かせてよ「夢は叶うんだ」って
Hey, let me hear you say, "Dreams do come true."
諦めが完敗 ならば絶対にないよ
If giving up means complete defeat, absolutely not!
だめに邪魔されようと ためらわないで
Even if hindered by flaws, don't hesitate.
託された情熱を 落とさずに つないでく
Connecting the entrusted passion without dropping it,
そう 最後まで
Yes, until the very end.
フラッグに誓い 雄々しく はためいて
Swearing on the flag, flapping valiantly,
鳴りやまない ファンファーレ
An unceasing fanfare!
いつも心に 流れていた
Always flowing in my heart...
遠い未来へ 祈るようは
Praying toward the distant future,
忘れられない あの日々の後悔を
Chasing the unforgettable regrets of those days,
追いかけて 滑り込んだ この想い
Slipping in after them, this feeling...
青いソラに ふとあふれた 遠く 遠く
Suddenly overflowing into the blue sky, far, far away...
トレビアンナイト
[Title: Trebian Night]
終わらない 終わらない 仕事が山積み 終わらない
It never ends, work piles up, it never ends!
止まらない 止まらない それでも時間は止まらないよ
It doesn't stop, even so, time doesn't stop!
ヘッド ヘッド 溜まり溜まった ヘッド
Head, head, accumulated head...
電波 時々 バット コンボ メス 金属バット
Radio waves, sometimes a bat, a combo, a scalpel, a metal bat!
今日もて一杯 今日もて一杯 No more むち
Today is full to the brim, today is full to the brim, no more whip!
ギミギミ じゅうしィ
Gimme gimme juicy!
細えみたい 細えみたい はあ はあ
Looks slender, looks slender, hah, hah...
溜め息ブレスで Energy すり減るから
Sparing energy with sighs of breath...
自分自身に 厳しすぎじゃん
Aren't you being way too strict on yourself?
すぐさまヘラヘラ 劣等生
Instantly a grinning underachiever!
さっぱり足りない 自制心 自分自身と しっかり向き合う
Totally lacking self-restraint, facing yourself properly.
一番必要なものは トレビアン ごほうびちょうだい
What you need most is Trebian! Give me a reward!
点でコマうような リズムに バイバイしちゃえ
Say bye-bye to a rhythm that puzzles you!
ドレミファノートに ごらん
Look at the Doremifa notes!
ぎゅうぎゅう詰め込み ためどんどんフリーダム
Cramming it tight, building up freedom more and more!
オーライ オーライ 好きなもの食べ放題
All right, all right, eat whatever you like to your heart's content!
おきらくにしますの ほらもっともっとちょうだい 暴動
Make yourself comfortable, come on, give me more and more riots!
たまには空振り 見失った一歩
Sometimes swinging and missing, a lost step...
すり減る胸張り おおもり いらない
Worn out, puffing out my chest, large serving, I don't need it!
まやかしの甘い囁き
Sweet whispers of deception.
ハッピーになるため歌おう 声高らかに
Let's sing out loud to become happy!
自分自身がやっぱり一番
Ultimately, I am number one!
快感と欲求が平行線 望みはハッピーエンドレス
Pleasure and desires run parallel, my wish is a happy endless!
自分自身としっかり向き合う
Facing yourself properly,
我慢は体に毒だよ
Holding back is poison to the body!
トレビアン ごほうびちょうだい
Trebian! Give me a reward!
点でコマうような リズムに バイバイしちゃえ
Say bye-bye to a rhythm that puzzles you!
ドレミファノートに ごらん
Look at the Doremifa notes!
ぎゅうぎゅう詰め込み ためどんどんフリーダム
Cramming it tight, building up freedom more and more!
1 2 3 窮屈な空気で日和るストレス
1, 2, 3! Stress cowering in a stifling atmosphere...
状態異常警告から解放フレディ！
Freed from status abnormality warnings, Freddy!
もっと もっと もっと もっと まだまだ足りない
More, more, more, more, still not enough!
本日は欲望解放パーティナイト
Tonight is a desire-releasing party night!
乾杯！
Cheers!
トレビアンナイト どこへおびき出せ
Trés bien night, where will you lure me?
てんでバラバラなリズムにバイバイしちゃえ
Saying goodbye to all these scattered rhythms!
トレビアンナイト どこにどこに御馳走
Trés bien night, where is the feast?
ぎゅうぎゅう詰めだためどどんどんフリーダム
Crammed tight, but ever more freedom!
ぎゅうぎゅう詰めだためどどんどん好きになる
Crammed tight, but growing more fond of it!
輝夜の城で踊りたい
[Song: I Want to Dance in Kaguya's Castle]
おいで！おいで！誘惑のDance again
Come on in! Come on in! Won’t you dance with me again?
おいでよおいで！輝夜の城へ
Come on in! Come on in to Kaguya’s castle!
出逢いがあやつるミステリー
An encounter woven by mystery,
危険なペルソナ
A dangerous persona.
踊ろう！踊ろう！終わらないDance beat
Dance! Dance! To this endless dance beat!
踊ろうよ踊ろう！輝夜の城で
Let’s dance, let’s dance at Kaguya’s castle!
夜空を切りとるレーザービーム
Laser beams slicing through the night sky,
私と見てよ？
Won’t you watch with me?
まどい星が照らす想い
Feelings illuminated by bewildered stars,
今宵の夢よ永遠に
May tonight’s dream last forever.
明日のことは忘れたいの
I want to forget about tomorrow.
私は紅い薔薇の姫よ
I am the princess of crimson roses,
優しくさらわれたい
Wanting to be gently swept away.
そっと囁いて
Whisper softly to me,
意味ありげに目をそらす
And avert your eyes with a meaningful look.
あなたは白い月の騎士
You are the knight of the white moon,
触れた手がまだ熱い
The hand that touched mine is still warm.
のがさずに抱きしめて
Hold me close and don't let me go,
この奇跡を恋と呼ぶのね
Calling this miracle "love," aren't you?
おいで！おいで！情熱でDance again
Come on in! Come on in! With passion, dance again!
おいでよおいで！輝夜の城へ
Come on in! Come on in to Kaguya’s castle!
迷いを飲みこむエナジー
Energy swallowing up all hesitation,
眠るなパッショネイト
A sleepless passionate night!
踊ろう！踊ろう！止まらないDance beat
Dance! Dance! To this unstoppable dance beat!
踊ろうよ踊ろう！輝夜の城で
Let’s dance, let’s dance at Kaguya’s castle!
星座が織りなすディスコティーク
A discotheque woven by the constellations,
私も混ぜて？
Won’t you let me join in too?
きらめく星に誓う心
A heart swearing upon the glittering stars,
儚い夢でいいわ
Even a fleeting dream is fine.
明日は明日の風が吹くの
Tomorrow's wind will blow tomorrow.
私は黒い薔薇の姫よ
I am the princess of black roses,
激しくさらわれたい
Wanting to be wildly swept away.
だから微笑んで
So smile at me,
追いかけてと目が誘う
And let your eyes invite me to chase you.
あなたも黒い月の騎士
You too are the knight of the black moon,
瞳の奥は熱い
The depths of your eyes are burning.
つかまえて抱きしめて
Catch me and hold me tight,
この奇跡は恋を呼ぶのね
Calling this miracle "love," aren't you?
一緒に行こう 急いでよ
Let's go together, hurry up!
よその人は見ちゃいや 私だけを見て
Don't look at anyone else, look only at me!
後悔するわよ
You'll regret it, you know!
楽しみをもっと早くしなさいよ
Hurry up and have more fun!
眠いのですね
You're sleepy, aren't you?
いいの？
Is that alright?
私は紅い薔薇の姫よ
I am the princess of crimson roses,
優しくさらわれたい
Wanting to be gently swept away.
そっと囁いて
Whisper softly to me,
意味ありげに目をそらす
And avert your eyes with a meaningful look.
あなたは白い月の騎士
You are the knight of the white moon,
触れた手がまだ熱い
The hand that touched mine is still warm.
のがさずに抱きしめて
Hold me close and don't let me go,
この奇跡を恋と呼ぶのね
Calling this miracle "love," aren't you?
おいで! おいで! 誘惑の Dance again
Come here! Come here! Tempting dance again
おいでよおいで! 輝夜の城へ
Come on, come here! To Kaguya's castle
出逢いが彩るミステリー
A mystery colored by our meeting
危険なペルソナ
A dangerous persona
踊ろう! 踊ろう! 終わらない Dance beat
Let's dance! Let's dance! Endless dance beat
踊ろうよ踊ろう! 輝夜の城で
Let's dance, let's dance! In Kaguya's castle
夜空を切りとるレーザービーム
A laser beam cutting through the night sky
私と見てよ?
Won't you watch with me?
まぶゆい星が照らす想い 今宵の夢よ永遠に
Feelings illuminated by dazzling stars, may tonight's dream last forever
ということで、3期生のみんなと「輝夜の城で踊りたい」を歌って踊りました！
So, we sang and danced to "I Want to Dance in Kaguya's Castle" with the 3rd gen!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ノエルちゃん、お誕生日おめでとう！ありがとう！
Noel-chan, happy birthday! Thank you!
ちょっと可愛いんじゃなーい？
Isn't it a bit cute?
はい、可愛い！
Yes, cute!
ちょっとね、あの、素敵に。はい、いかがですか？可愛いですか？
A bit, you know, wonderfully. Yes, how is it? Is it cute?
可愛いー！
So cute!
おっぱいがお尻だよ、マリン！
Your boobs are your butt, Marine!
こんなのおっぱいに挨拶しちゃってさ
Saying hello to boobs like that...
ぺこらさあ、こう話せばいいのかな？
Pekora, like, how should I talk like this?
違う違う！こういうことこういうこと！
No, no! Like this, like this!
ええと、あ、今回のね、衣装はね、あの、200万人記念でね、作っていただきました。
Um, ah, this costume was made to commemorate 2 million subscribers.
他にもね、変わったところ、今日のライブからであるんだけど
There are other changes starting from today's live, but...
え、マリンも怒ってる？え？え？
Eh, is Marine mad too? Eh? Eh?
え、気づいた？
Eh, you noticed?
そうなんです、ちょっと目変わります。え、大丈夫ですか？
That's right, my eyes changed a bit. Eh, is that okay?
全然違うじゃん！
It's totally different!
ちなみに、お気に入りの顔がありまして、ちょっとね
By the way, I have a favorite face, and you know...
あの、お困り顔、お困り顔がね、そう、可愛いので、お口がね、こうリボンになってるんです。
That troubled face, that troubled face is so cute, my mouth is shaped like a ribbon.
あ、本当だ！
Ah, true!
こだわりなんだね。可愛い！
It's aこだわり. Cute!
ええ、じゃあちょっと衣装、せっかくなんで
Eh, well, since we have the chance, let's check the costume...
下からちょっと舐めるように、いきますよ。
Let's look from the bottom up.
靴から見ましょう、靴から。
Let's look at the shoes first, from the shoes.
おら、可愛い！お靴いいでしょ？
Look, cute! Aren't the shoes nice?
ちょっとよく見せて。あ、ほら、リボンなんだね。
Show me closely. Ah, look, it's a ribbon.
可愛い！リボン付いてる！
Cute! It has a ribbon!
普段はね、通常でペッタンコだからちょっと身長も盛りました。
Normally it's flat, so I added a bit to my height.
リボン、2個前、後ろにね。
Two ribbons, in front and back.
そうなんです。付いてます。
That's right. They're attached.
いいねいいね、じゃあちょっと舐めるように
Nice, nice, then let's look closely...
上がって、上がって、上がって。うわー、一体どんなおパンツ...
Moving up, up, up. Whoa, what kind of pant...
可愛い！何これ、変態もの？
Cute! What is this, perverted?
好奇心が...
Curiosity is...
え、こんな感じで、え、まだ舐めてる最中？まだ舐めてる最中？
Eh, like this, eh, still licking? Still licking?
あ、待って待って、まだ舐めてる最中！あ、ここね、ここ、ノエルじゃない！
Ah, wait wait, still licking! Ah, right here, right here, this isn't Noel!
ノエルじゃない、ノエルじゃない。
Not Noel, not Noel.
ここ、皆さんご覧ください、ここ、ここ、この、この、この、胸のこの隙間、隙間！
Look at this, everyone, right here, this gap in the chest!
隙間ね、分かります？
The gap, you know it?
この乳と乳の間... 本当だ、すごいね、隙間がね！
Between these breasts... Wow, amazing, there's a gap!
うわー！大、大丈夫ですか？
Whoa! I-Is that okay?
大丈夫大丈夫。ね、最高の衣装でしょ。
It's fine, it's fine. Right, it's the best costume.
じゃあちょっと上を見せるにあたって、このね、ヒラヒラ取れるから
So to show the top part, these ruffles are removable...
可愛い、それ。ちょっと取ってもいい？
That's cute. Can I take it off?
取ってください！あ、取った！
Please take it off! Ah, took it off!
おお、お目見えだ。そう、なんです。万歳！
Oh, revealed. That's right. Yay!
え、横はどうなってるの？ゆっくりくるくる回って。
Eh, what does the side look like? Turn around slowly.
くるくるくるくる... 可愛い！
Spin spin spin... Cute!
髪の毛もフワフワで可愛い！
Her hair is fluffy and cute too!
新衣装の秘密はね...
The secret of the new costume is...
こう、リボンが髪に、こう、巻き込んであって。
The ribbon is wrapped into her hair like this.
そうなんです。編み込んで。エロラッチョも...
That's right. Braided in. Ecchi-latte also...
姫騎士なんでね、お姫様...
Because she's a princess knight, a princess...
なってまーす！
That's how it is!
可愛すぎる！こんなの好きになっちゃう。
Too cute! I'm gonna fall for this.
ちょっと変えるかしたいから、いつもの動きして。
I want to change it up, so do your usual move.
待ってて、待ってて。あ！
Wait, wait. Ah!
なんか好きじゃなくなっちゃった！
Suddenly I don't like it anymore!
危ない危ない、恋するとこだった。
Phew, close one, almost fell in love.
いや、でも本当に可愛い衣装。本当。
No, but truly a cute costume. Really.
おめでとう！いいかも、マジで。
Congratulations! This is really good, seriously.
みんなにはちょっとアイドル衣装だったんですけど... そう、みんなもさ、衣装持ってるじゃん。並んだりとかも今後したいな。
So for everyone it was idol costumes, but... Everyone has costumes too. I'd love for us to line up together in the future.
え、絶対やりたい！
Eh, I definitely want to do that!
すりすりして、また歌って踊りたいな！
Rub against each other, and sing and dance again!
え、ちょっとそれ、全然分かんない！あったかな？
Eh, wait, I don't get that at all! Was there?
はい、ということで、ここから大事なお知らせをたくさんしていきます。お願いします！
Yes, so from here we'll make a lot of important announcements. Please!
日時ですが、2026年1月17日と18日の2日間にわたって開催されます！
The date is held over two days, January 17 and 18, 2026!
会場はね、あの、でっかい、そう、Kアリーナ横浜となってます。
The venue is, you know, huge, yeah, K Arena Yokohama.
昨日ね、なんと、ちょっと二次先行...
Yesterday, amazingly, the secondary pre-order...
みたいなん で ちょっと ね まだまだ 諦め ず に ね
Like that, so don't give up yet!
ぬえ ちゃん 大変 だ と 思う けど
I think it's tough for Noel-chan,
ぜひ ぜひ あの ね どうぞ ください お願い し ます
but please, please go ahead. Please!
お 願い し ます お 願い し ます
Please! Please!
そして 配信 チケット は ね まだ あり ます ので はい 絶賛 発売 中 です の で よろしく お 願い いたし ます お 願い し ます
Also, streaming tickets are still available, so please check them out! Please!
そして ま この ライブ を 見 て くださっ た 方 で
And for those who watched this live stream...
ま 会 忘れ てる 人 は いない と 思う けど
well, I don't think anyone forgot,
あの グッズ の ね 先行 販売 と 受注 販売 も 明日 の ね え 11 月 25 日 の 18 時 まで と なっ て おり ます
but the advance and made-to-order merchandise sales end tomorrow, November 25th at 6 PM!
明日 ね そう だ から
Tomorrow, yes. So,
あの ライブ 会場 で ペン ライト 振り たい と か 配信 見 ながら ペン ライト 振り たい よっ て 人 は ぜひ この 機会 を お 見逃し なく
if you want to wave penlights at the venue or while watching the stream, don't miss this chance!
現地 行く 人 は 是非 とも 絶対 絶対 って 言っ た 方 が 盛り上がり ます よ お 願い し ます お 願い し ます お 願い し ます
Those going in person, definitely, absolutely go! It gets so much more exciting, please! Please! Please!
いや 楽しみ だ ね めっちゃ 楽しみ
Man, I'm so excited! Super excited!
そう 男 も ね ちょっと お メイク を 変え た から
Yeah, and Dancho also changed up her makeup a bit,
ライブ の 楽しみ
so looking forward to it!
せっかく ね 来 て くれ た から 意気込み を 一言 ちょっと 一言 ね
Since you came all this way, let's hear a word of enthusiasm from everyone!
くそる や だ から 行く な くそる やる気 満々 だ ぞ
Dammit! Why are you going?! Dammit! I'm full of motivation!
え じゃあ ちょっと マリン から こう いう 順番 で
Alright, so starting from Marine in this order!
すごい いい こと 言っ て くれる だろう な
I'm sure she'll say something really great!
頑張る ぞ
I'll do my best!
楽しみ ぞ
I'm excited!
みんな で メリ上げる ぞ
Let's get everyone hyped up!
ありがとう
Thank you!
光 の 速さ で 去っ て いっ た みんな ありがとう
She vanished at the speed of light! Thank you, everyone!
ってな 感じ で ここ から は ノエ ちゃん の 告知 に 行き ます まず 1 つ 目 は こちら
With that, let's move on to Noel-chan's announcements! First one is this!
はい 今年 も 出 ます 白金 の える 誕生日 記念 2025 の グッズ は い
Yes, they're coming out this year too! The Shirogane Noel Birthday Commemoration 2025 goods! Yay!
え 全段 グッズ まず は こちら はい 睡魔 の 世界 へ キラキラ LED アト パネル
First up is this! The "Into the Realm of the Sleep Demon" sparkly LED art panel!
イラスト は ミョンイ 先生 が 描い て くれ まし た ありがとう ござい ます いつも お世話 に なっ て ます ラブチ ラブチ
Illustrated by MyungYi-sensei, thank you so much! Always appreciate your work, love ya!
今回 の ね 聖誕 ライブ の ステージ と 新書 が テーマ に なっ て おり ます
This time, the theme is based on the stage and new song of this birthday live!
LED と いう こと で こちら 光る と いう こと で あの 是非 お 部屋 に 飾っ て 今回 の ライブ を 思い出し て 思い出 に し て ください
As an LED item, it lights up, so please decorate your room with it and remember this live performance!
はい そして 次 は こちら いろんな のえ ちゃん ランダム マルチ バンド と いう こと で 丸 先生 が 描い て くれ まし た ありがとう ござい ます
Yes, and next is this: the "Various Noel-chan Random Multi-Band," illustrated by Maru Eri-sensei! Thank you so much!
いや いろんな のえ ちゃん が い ます ので どの のえ ちゃん が お 家 に 来る か なっ て 楽しみ に し つつ 届い たら マルチ バンド こちら お 片付け の 必須 品 と なっ て おり ます のえ ちゃん も 使っ て おり ます の で ぜひ コード まとめる 時 と か 実用 性 に 飛ん で ます ので 使っ て み て ください
Since there are various Noel-chans, while looking forward to which Noel-chan will come home to you, once it arrives, these multi-bands are essential for tidying up! Noel uses them too, so please use them when wrapping cords—they're very practical!
次 は こちら 姫騎士 ノエル ぬいぐるみ キーホルダー と いう こと で
Next is this: the Himekishi Noel plushie keychain!
昨年 は サンタ さん の のえ ちゃん が ぬいぐるみ と し て キーホルダー 出 た ん です が 今回 は せっかく 新書 が 出 た の で こちら で ぬいぐるみ キーホルダー を 作り まし た
Last year, we released a Santa Noel plushie keychain, but since we have a new song this time, we made a new plushie keychain!
姫騎士 と し て 大切 を 守り ます ので ぜひ 肌身離さ ず モテ て ください
As a Himekishi protecting your precious things, please keep it close to you always!
次 は こちら わんちょむ 2way ネック ピロー と いう こと で
Next is this: the Wanchomu 2-way neck pillow!
安眠 に 最適 な ネック ピロー な ん です けど 今回 は なん と ひっくり返す と わんちょむ に なっ て いる と いう こと で
It's a neck pillow ideal for a good sleep, but this time, if you flip it inside out, it turns into Wanchomu!
まあ わんちょむ は 今年 から 団長 の お 家 に お 迎え し た わん ちゃん の こと な ん です けど グッズ に し ちゃい まし た ちょっと のえ ちゃん の 市長 が 入っ て ます と いう こと で ぜひ 団長 の お 家 に も 迎え て ください
Wanchomu is the dog that joined Dancho's family this year, and we made it into merchandise! It has a bit of Noel's personal push behind it, so please welcome it into your home too!
最後 に フル セット を 見 て み ましょう こちら 今年 も いっぱい いっぱい グッズ が 出 まし た
Finally, let's look at the full set! Lots of goods came out this year too!
いや 是非 是非 ゲット し て み て ね そして この 全部 の フル セット 特典 が あり ます それ は こちら
Please definitely check them out! And there's a bonus for the full set. Here it is!
と いう こと で フル セット を 購入 し て くださっ た 方 に チェキ 風 ブロマイド カード 付い てき ます
For those who purchase the full set, aチェキ-style bromide card will be included!
いや とっても 素敵 ま イラスト は ミョンイ 先生 の イラスト で こちら に 通常 バージョン は 白押し の 複製 サイン が
It's wonderful! Illustrated by MyungYi-sensei. The regular version has a foil-stamped duplicate signature,
数量 限定 バージョン は 団長 の 直筆 サイン が 付い てき ます 心 を 込め て 書き ます ので ぜひ ゲット し て み て ください
while the limited quantity version comes with Dancho's handwritten signature! Written with all my heart, so please grab one!
さらに さらに さらに フル セット を 購入 し て くれ た 方 全員 に 特典 ボイス も 付い てき ちゃい ます フル セット の なん か ちょっと 欲しい て みんな 思っ た ん じゃ ない でしょ う か 是非 ゲット し て み て ください ボイス
Furthermore, everyone who purchases the full set will also get a bonus voice track! I'm sure you all want the full set now, right? Please grab yours!
胸を込めて撮ります！
I'll put my heart into taking it!
よろしくお願いします！
Thank you very much!
生誕グッズは22時カートオープンです。
The birthday merch cart opens at 22:00.
皆さんぜひゲットしてください！おねがいします。
Everyone, please be sure to get it! I'm counting on you.
さらにさらに重大告知があります。
And furthermore, I have a major announcement.
なんとそれは……ずんずんずんずんずんずん、はい！新曲があります！
Guess what... zun-zun-zun-zun-zun-zun, yes! There's a new song!
で、その新曲をね、発表するに当たって、なんと……なんかちょっと今回ちょっとスペシャルな方からね、コメントをちょっといただいてるみたいなのだけど、
And, to announce that new song, amazingly... It seems we've received comments from someone rather special this time, but
なだんだけど、え、誰なんだろう？ちょっとノエルわかんないな。誰でしょうか？
who could it be? Noel has no idea. Who could it be?
え！？待って、うわ、すっごいキラキラしてる！
Eh?! Wait, wow, it's super sparkling!
こまっする～！
Komassuru~!
白銀ノエルさん、お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Shirogane Noel-san, happy birthday!
おめでとうございます。
Happy birthday.
そして団員の皆さん、配信を楽しんでいらっしゃいますか？
And to all the corps members, are you enjoying the stream?
大分県知事の佐藤樹一郎です。
I'm Kiichiro Sato, Governor of Oita Prefecture.
なに？ちっちい？
What? Tiny?
めじろんです！
I'm Meji-ron!
この度は新曲の発表もおめでとうございます。
Congratulations on the announcement of your new song as well.
今回、私たちがノエルさんの新曲のタイトル発表を任せていただける・ことになりました。
This time, we have been entrusted with announcing the title of Noel-san's new song.
任せてくれるんですか！？
You're going to let us do it?!
それでは早速、曲名を発表したいと思います。
Now then, I'd like to promptly announce the song title.
その名も……VAVAVA！バーチャル大分！
That name is... VAVAVA! Virtual Oita!
バーチャル大分わーい！
Virtual Oita, yay!
そうですね、「バーチャル大分」と入っていますので、大分をバーチャルで楽しめるような歌なのかな？
That's right, since it includes "Virtual Oita", I wonder if it's a song where you can enjoy Oita virtually?
はい、そうです。
Yes, that's right.
はい！大分のおすすめ、たくさんありますよ！
Yes! There are lots of recommendations in Oita!
まずは、なんと言っても温泉です！
First of all, hot springs above all!
大分県は源泉数、湧出ともに全国1位ですから！
Because Oita Prefecture ranks #1 in both hot spring sources and output!
他にも、関アジや関サバ、かぼすブリ、おいた和牛、からあげなんかの食の魅力も満載ですね。
And the culinary charms are packed, like Seki horse mackerel, Seki mackerel, kabosu yellowtail, Oita Wagyu, and karaage.
ぜひ、皆さんにも味わっていただきたいです！
I definitely want everyone to taste them too!
はい！
Yes!
ノエルさん！大分を代表して応援しちょんけん！これからも大分県のPRを頼むけんね！
Noel-san! I'm rooting for you representing Oita! Please keep promoting Oita!
え、ありがとうございます！新曲、しんけん楽しみしちょんけん！
Eh, thank you very much! I'm really looking forward to the new song!
それでは、おつまっする～！
Well then, Otsumassuru~!
おつおつまっする～！
Otsu otsu massuru~!
あ、めじろんも！おつまっする、おつまっする！ということで、
Ah, Meji-ron too! Otsumassuru, otsumassuru! And so,
まさかの意外や意外、大分県知事の佐藤樹一郎さんに新曲のタイトル発表と応援のコメントをいただきました！ありがとうございます！
surprisingly and unexpectedly, we received the new song title announcement and cheering comments from Oita Prefecture Governor Kiichiro Sato! Thank you very much!
あの、これ本当にあのノエルちゃんびっくりで、本当にこれさ、サプライズなんですけれど
This was really, you know, a huge surprise for Noel-chan! It's truly a surprise, but...
いや本当にありがとうございます。まさかこんな日が来るなんてっていうことで、いや本当にすごい方からあの応援していただいて嬉しいですね。
I truly thank you. Never did I imagine such a day would come, so I'm really happy to be supported by such an amazing person.
ちょ団長本当何が起こったのか最初わからず。いやしかめじろんも横にいて、あのね、あの緑の、そう、いましてね、すごく可愛かったなと思います。
As Commander, at first I didn't even understand what was happening. And Meji-ron was right there, you know, that green one, yeah, it was there, and I thought it was super cute.
あの本当にね、あの、あの、ずっとあの団長大分育ちで、はい、あの、大分の魅力をばーっと配信でね、あの個人的に言ってるだけなんですけれど
Honestly, you know, Danchou grew up in Oita, and yeah, I'm just personally blabbing on stream about Oita's charm, but...
いや本当日頃ね大分の魅力を伝えてきてよかったなと思います。
I really think it's been great conveying Oita's charm on a daily basis.
あの、もちろんこれからもあの個人的、特に何か大きなことがあるわけではなく、あの個人的に、はい、あの団長大分の魅力をあの伝えていきたいなと思いますので、皆さんもまだ大分に行ったことない人は、ぜひ大いに行ってきてください！
Of course, from now on too, not that there's any particular huge thing, but personally, yeah, Danchou wants to keep conveying Oita's charm, so everyone who hasn't been to Oita yet, please definitely go check out Oita!
いいところだよ～！
It's a great place~!
ということで、あの新曲うたっちゃいたいと思います！え、聞いてください！VAVAVA！バーチャル大分！
With that, I'd like to sing the new song! Uh, please listen! VAVAVA! Virtual Oita!
説明しよう。バーチャル大分とは、バーチャル九州の北東部に位置する広大な大地。現実の大分県に限りなく近い地上の楽園。人はその地をバーチャル大分と呼ぶ。
Let us explain. Virtual Oita is a vast land located in the northeastern part of Virtual Kyushu. A paradise on earth almost indistinguishable from real Oita Prefecture. People call that land Virtual Oita.
VAVAVA! バーチャル大分 世に放つ
VAVAVA! Virtual Oita, unleashed upon the world!
バーチャル大分 湯を沸かせ 君とバーチャル大分 駆け巡る
Virtual Oita, boil the hot springs! Roaming around Virtual Oita with you!
VAVAVA! バーチャル大分 ドーン！
VAVAVA! Virtual Oita, boom!
大分 ドーン！
Oita, boom!
君は降り立つ 魅惑の地獄の入り口 絶えず湧く湧く 魅惑の地獄
You touch down at the entrance of the bewitching hells, where bewitching hells constantly bubble up!
海地獄 かまど地獄 竜巻地獄 鬼石坊主 鬼山 竜巻 パーン！
Sea Hell, Kamado Hell, Tornado Hell, Oniishi Bozu, Oniyama, Tatsumaki, pop!
とり天 とりめし やせうま だんご汁 中津からあげ 冷麺 関アジ 関サバ
Toriten, torimeshi, yaseuma, dangojiru, Nakatsu karaage, reimen, Seki horse mackerel, Seki mackerel
かぼす あつめし まだまだ入るよ
Kabosu, atsumeshi, there's still room for more!
鉄の胃袋 大魔神！
Iron stomach, Great Majin!
行こうぜ久重高原 湯煙の温泉
Let's go to Kuju Highlands, hot spring of steam!
高崎山に
Takasakiyama,
金鱗湖
Kinrin Lake,
青の洞門
Ao no Domon,
由布 由布川渓谷
Yufu, Yufugawa Gorge,
進め
Move forward,
稲積水中鍾乳洞
to Inazuki Underwater Limestone Cave!
果てしなき旅
An endless journey,
独り歩き遠足
a solo walking excursion.
たどり着くさ
We'll arrive at last,
食べる弁当
to eat our bento box.
時空を超えた奇跡の土地
A miraculous land transcending spacetime,
バーチャル大分 いくぞー！
Virtual Oita, let's go!
バーチャル大分いたように放つ
Virtual Oita, unleash it as if you're there,
バーチャル大分いた湯湧かす君と
Virtual Oita, boiling hot springs with you,
バーチャル大分いたかけめぐれ
Virtual Oita, running all around,
バーチャル大分いた大分どん！
Virtual Oita, Oita, bang!
バーチャル大分いたように放つ
Virtual Oita, unleash it as if you're there,
バーチャル大分いた食べ尽くす君と
Virtual Oita, eating everything up with you,
バーチャル大分いたかけめぐれ
Virtual Oita, running all around,
バーチャル大分いた大分どん！
Virtual Oita, Oita, bang!
よだきい しょうしい えらしい
Yodakī, shōshī, erashī,
しんけん やおねぇ ふがわり なしか
shinken, yaonē, fugawari, nashika,
むげねぇ せせろしい こまっそ
mugenē, sesoroshii, komasso.
だけどあんた いまなにしょん？ こまっそ
But what are you doing right now, komasso?
説明しよう！
Let me explain!
バーチャル大分観光大使とはバーチャル大分への深い郷土愛を持ち、その魅力を余すところなく伝え続ける存在。
The Virtual Oita Tourism Ambassador has deep love for Oita and shares its charm fully.
人はその大使の名をバーチャル大分観光大使と呼ぶ！
People call this ambassador the Virtual Oita Tourism Ambassador!
バーチャル大分 Oh! I wanna be a 観光大使
Virtual Oita, Oh! I wanna be a tourism ambassador!
バーチャル大分いたように放つ
Virtual Oita, unleash it as if you're there,
バーチャル大分いた湯を湧かす君と
Virtual Oita, boiling hot springs with you,
バーチャル大分いたかけめぐれ
Virtual Oita, running all around,
バーチャル大分いた大分どん！
Virtual Oita, Oita, bang!
バーチャル大分いたように放つ
Virtual Oita, unleash it as if you're there,
バーチャル大分いた食べ尽くす君と
Virtual Oita, eating everything up with you,
バーチャル大分いたかけめぐれ
Virtual Oita, running all around,
バーチャル大分いた大分どん！
Virtual Oita, Oita, bang!